Let's get started with the second day of our special week.
It's day 17 for the month of September.
Hi, everyone. I'm Steve Sareisi.
And I'm Jenny Skidmore. Thanks for joining us.
Special week, second day.
Let's train your sprinting ability with this training.
SPR Robics.
それはリズムに乗って即座に英語で表現するトレーニングです。
今回は新しく買った服についての会話がテーマです。
Let's try phrases from a conversation about clothes.
それでは僕が言う日本語をビートに乗って英語で瞬時に表現してみてください。
You can do it!
Alright, let's get started!
ただいまー。
Welcome back.
How are you?
I'm fine. Where have you been?
Shopping.
What did you buy?
I bought a shirt.
You bought a shirt again?
It's a check shirt.
Another check shirt?
This is a different one.
Can I look at it?
Sure.
Ta-da!
No comment.
You don't like it, do you?
It's not bad.
This one has an orange color.
You can tell by looking at it.
Orange is an autumn color.
Well, it's a nice shirt.
Huh? Where are you going?
I'm going shopping too.
What are you going to buy?
My new autumn clothes.
Have you ever bought something new, and then, when you got home, maybe something similar was already in your closet?
I know that's happened to me quite a few times, Steve.
そうですね。同じようなものを買ってしまうことはありますよね。皆さんいかがですか?
それではここでジェニーさんに今回のエスピアロビクスに挑んでもらいます。
それぞれ英語でどのように表現するのか チェックしてみてください
OK, listen closely
ただいま
I'm home
おかえり
Welcome back
げんき?
How you doing?
げんきだよ どこにいてたの?
Good, where'd you go?
おかえもの
I went shopping
何を買ったの?
What'd you get?
シャツを買ったよ。
I got a shirt.
またシャツを買ったの?
You got another shirt?
チェックのシャツだよ。
It's a plaid shirt.
またチェックのシャツ?
Another plaid shirt?
これは違うもの。
This one is different.
見てもいい?
Can I see it?
いいよ。じゃじゃーん。
Sure。
タダー。
No commentです。
I have no comment.
気に入らないんだね。
You don't like it.
まあ、悪くないね。
Well, it's not bad.
これにはオレンジ色が入っている。
This has orange in it.
見ればわかるよ。
I can see that.
オレンジは秋の色だし。
Orange is a fall color.
まあ、素敵なシャツだね。
Well, it is a nice shirt.
あれ、どこに行くの?
Hey, where are you going?
私も買い物に行ってくる。
I'm going shopping too.
何を買うの?
What are you going to buy?
私の新しい秋の服
New fall clothes for me
So, did you understand how to express those phrases?
では、ここでいくつかの表現を確認しましょう
まず、日本語のただいま、おかえり
I'm home, welcome back
そこスムーズにぜひ言ってくださいね
その後、元気?
元気?
これを英語で言うとHow are you? あるいはHow are you doing? これがスタンダードですが会話表現としてYouをやにしてHow are you doing? また同じような会話表現としてWhere did you go? を言うとWhere did you go? もちろんWhere did you go? でも大丈夫です。
そして日本語でシャツと聞くともしかしてシャーツと複数形で表現してしまうかもしれないんですけれども今回は
単数形のshirt
例えばシャツを買ったよっていうのは
I got a shirt
I bought a shirt でもいいです
そして楽しい表現ありましたね
ジャジャーンっていうのは
タダー
一回ジェニーさんのあたりに行ってみよう
そしてノーコメントですっていうのは
ノーコメントだけでもいいんですが
このような文でよく使います
I have no comment
タダー
そして会話の最後の方に、私も買い物に行ってくる。
I'm going shopping too.
このスタンダードな文、ちゃんと言えるように頑張ってください。
それでは皆さん、このエスピアロビクスにもう一度チャレンジしましょう。
OK, everyone. It's time for your second try. Let's go.
ただいま。
おかえり。
How are you doing?
I'm fine.
Where have you been?
Shopping.
What did you buy?
I bought a shirt.
You bought a shirt again?
It's a check shirt.
Also, checkered shirt?
This is a different one.
Can I see it?
Sure.
Ta-da!
No comment.
You don't like it, do you?
Well, it's not bad, is it?
This one has an orange color in it.
I can tell by looking at it.
Orange is the color of autumn.
Well, it's a nice shirt.
Huh? Where are you going?
I'm going shopping too.
何を買うの?
私の新しい秋の服。
OK. Great job, everyone.
Were you able to say those phrases a little better than your first time around?
Thanks for practicing speaking with SPROvics.
二日目のSPROvics、お疲れ様でした。
さて、明日はイディオム集中特訓です。
覚えていくと便利なイディオムを身につけて、
文の形で表現できるようになりましょう。
So everyone, get on board.
And let's practice speaking together.
See you next time on...
英会話タイムトライアル。
バイバイ。